import { Question } from "@/types/Questions";

export const questions: Question[] = [
    {
        question: "which atom component has negative carge?",
        options: ["proton", "neutron", "electron", "quark"],
        answer: 2
    },
    {
        question: "what's current atomic model?",
        options: ["dalton", "bohr", "rutherford", "schrödinger"],
        answer: 3
    },
    {
        question: "who's discovery radioactivy?",
        options: ["marie", "pierre", "eisnten", "lavosier"],
        answer: 0
    },
    {
        question: "which component is responsible for obtaining energy from the sun?",
        options: ["clorofile", "membrane", "thylakoid", "nucleus"],
        answer: 0
    },
    {
        question: "what's the molecule form of glicose?",
        options: ["C₈H₁₀N₄O₂", "C₁₂H₂₂O₁₁", "C₆H₁₂O₆", "H₂O₂"],
        answer: 2
    },
    {
        question: "which the most massive object in the universe?",
        options: ["pulsar", "neutron star", "quasar", "black hole"],
        answer: 3
    },
    {
        question: "which nitrogenous base is not present in rna?",
        options: ["thymine", "uracile", "gunanine", "adenine"],
        answer: 0
    },
    {
        question: "how many generations does quarks have?",
        options: ["1", "2", "3", "4"],
        answer: 2
    },
    {
        question: "what's the name of the component that makes the electrical signal in neurons fast?",
        options: ["protein", "axions", "myelin sheath", "dendrites"],
        answer: 2
    },
    {
        question: "what's the light velocity in m/s",
        options: ["4x10⁸", "3x10⁵", "2x10⁸", "3x10⁸"],
        answer: 3
    }
]